WILLIAM KENNEDY PAPERS (MSS132) 1926-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Ironweed, 1970; 1978-1982; 2003; Undated; 4; 1.26 cu. ft.
  - Edited Pages with Notes, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Second Draft, Viking Press Copy, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Incomplete Second Draft, Pages 124-255, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Master Copy of Second Draft, with Edits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carbon Copy Pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Final Draft with Typesetters Notes (Folder 1 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Final Draft with Typesetters Notes (Folder 2 of 2), Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs, ca. 1982 (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Pages Pulled for University at Albany Speech, October 29, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- O Albany!: Improbable City of Political Wizards, Fearless Ethnics, Spectacular Aristocrats, Splendid Nobodies, and Underrated Scoundrels, 1953-2002; Undated; 5; 2.34 cu. ft.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Published in 1983, William Kennedy's nonfiction work O Albany! is based upon a series of articles he wrote about the city for the Albany Times-Union in the early-mid 1960s, which garnered him a Pulitzer Prize nomination for journalism. The book looks at Albany neighborhoods, different ethnic and racial groups who settled within the city, landmarks and institutions, and key political leaders. The series includes manuscripts and draft copy, Kennedy's earlier newspaper features, research materials and notes. As all the materials span a significant amount of time, please note the overall dates for this series are not inclusive.
  - Unfinished Draft of "Albany: Worst County, Longest Run", Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - One Draft of "Albany, Why Albany?", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nine Drafts of "Arbor Hill", Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - One Draft of "Being Irish", Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Six Drafts of "Blacks", Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Documents Regarding "Blacks", 1963-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Blacks", 1990; 1997; 2000-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Author Notes for "Blacks/Poverty", 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Blacks/Poverty", 1965-1966; 1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eight Drafts of "Bonafettle", Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Four Drafts of "The Blvd. of Bluest Dreams", Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Copy of 1980 Census, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Three Drafts of "Capitol Hill", Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nine Drafts of "Central Avenue", Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Working Drafts for "The Changing Face of Albany", Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Changing Face of Albany" News Clips, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Working Draft of "Debts and Butterings", Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts of "Delaware Avenue I", Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nine Drafts of "Delaware Avenue II", Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One Draft of "The Democrats Convene", Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nine Drafts of "Downtown", Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Eight Drafts of "Epilogue", Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Three Drafts of "Erastus" with Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Two Incomplete Drafts of "Erastus", Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Complete Master Copy of "Erastus", Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Working Draft for "The Last Word/Erastus", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Research on Ethnic Groups, 1966-1999 (Oversized 5, Folder 1-2)
  - News Clippings on Various Ethnic Groups, 1988; 1990; 1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Literature and Notes Regarding Germans, 1953; 1981-1982; 1990; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Greeks" Personal Correspondence, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Eight Drafts of "Introduction", Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - News Clips Regarding "Sons of St. Patrick", 1963; 1987-1989; 1996; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Documents Regarding Ireland and "The Irish", 1991-1992; 1994; 1997; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - News Clips Regarding "The Irish", 1963; 1976; 1981; 1990; Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Draft of Article "South End Italians," Articles 1 and 2, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Six Drafts of "The Italians", Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - News Clips Regarding "Italians", 1981; 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Three Drafts of "Jews", Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "South End Jews," Articles 1 and 3, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Research Documents Regarding "Jews", 1957-1982; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Author Notes Regarding "Jews", Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Jews", 1963-1964; 1976; 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Six Drafts of "Legs", Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Five Drafts of "The Mall Also Rises", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Three Drafts of "Nighttown", Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Seven Drafts of "North Albany", Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Two Drafts of "A Walk on the Waters of Gander Bay", Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Two Drafts of "The Absolutely Last Hurrah is Yet to Come", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Six Drafts of "Dan I", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Five Drafts of "Dan II", Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - One Draft of "Dan II/They Bury the Boss", Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - One Draft of "O'Connell", Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - One Draft of "Sidebar: O'Dwyer on O'Connell", Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Five Drafts of "The Positively Last Hurrah Has Yet to be Heard", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Eight Drafts of "Pine Hills", Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Six Drafts of "Prohibition", Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Six Drafts of "Pruyn Connection I", Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Eight Drafts of "Pruyn Connection II", Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Eight Drafts of "South Mall", Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts and Master Copy of "South Mall", Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Four Drafts of "Sports and Swells", Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Theater, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Eight Writings on the Trinity Institution, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Trinity Institution December Schedule, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Five Drafts of "Union Station", Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Documents Covering "The War on Poverty", 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Four Drafts of "West End I", Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Four Drafts of "West End II", Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Four Drafts of "The Whorehouse Neighborhood", Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Charlie Malarkey Books, 1975-1998; 2001; Undated; 6; 1.03 cu. ft.
  This series contains materials related to two children's books that William Kennedy wrote with his son Brendan; Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, published in 1986, and Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, which appeared in print in 1993. The series features working and edited drafts, galleys, newspaper clippings, reviews, and press tour materials. There also are several folders of correspondence. The files document the difficulties Kennedy encountered in attempting to publish the first book, including many rejection letters from publishing houses beginning in 1975. Of additional interest is correspondence about illustrations, foreign editions, possible film deals, and letters and a book from children who enjoyed the stories.
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Rejection Letters, 1975-1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Four Working Drafts with Author Notes, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Five Edited Drafts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Seven Drafts of Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts of Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Illustration Correspondence and Information, 1985-1986; 1988; 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Atlantic Press Monthly Materials, 1986 (Oversized 5, Folder 3)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Atlantic Press Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Atlantic Monthly Press Book List, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Correspondence for Foreign Editions, 1986-1987; 1989-1990; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Personal Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine News Clippings, Articles, Reviews, 1986-1988; 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Publicity, 1986; 1990; 1993; 1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bubblegum Trees Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Film Project Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Sixteen Drafts with Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Junior Writer's Week Information and Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Fourteen Drafts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Nine Drafts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Thirteen Edited and Revised Drafts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - P.S. 16 Student Letters and Stories, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Related Materials, 1991; 1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Illustration Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Film Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose/Penguin Correspondence, 1991-1994; 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Edited Pages, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Final Copy and Three Revised Drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Galleys for Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, 1993 (Oversized 5, Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose New Choices Correspondence and Article Information, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Penguin Correspondence for Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Publicity Papers, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chandler School Class Reaction Letters, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Book Cover, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Author's Note, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Author Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book Made by Schoolchildren for Kennedy, Undated (Oversized 5, Folder 5)
- The Cotton Club, 1983-1986; 1988-1989; 1993; 1997; Undated; 7; 2.25 cu. ft.
  In the summer of 1983 William Kennedy accepted director Francis Ford Coppola's invitation to collaborate with him on a film script for The Cotton Club, a 1930s period drama built around the real Harlem night club in New York. He spent the remainder of that summer and the fall writing and editing, as the movie transitioned from the pre-production phase to principal photography. The film debuted in the United States in 1984. This series documents that intensive writing and re-writing effort with many working scripts, rehearsal scripts, shooting scripts, and editing scripts. In addition, there are production memos and notes, call sheets, publicity materials, reviews, correspondence, and a file about the movie premiere.
  - Revised Working Draft by Francis Ford Coppola Only, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rehearsal Draft, July 25 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rehearsal Draft with Revised Pages and Editing, July 25 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chronology of Scenes, July 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Call Sheets, July-November 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Call Sheets, August-November 1983 (Oversized 4, Folder 2)
  - Revised Rehearsal Draft, August 3 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sunday Afternoon Draft, Master Copy with Editing, August 7 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sunday Night Draft, August 7 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Estimating Draft, August 8 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Estimating Draft with Bob Evans Letter and Comments, August 8 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Monday Preview Draft, August 15 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shooting Script (Preliminary), August 16 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shooting Script, Saturday Night Draft, August 21 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shooting Script, August 22 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shooting Script, Sunday Night Draft, August 22 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shooting Script, Master Copy, August 22 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Revised Shooting Script, Working Draft, September 26 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Revised Shooting Script, September 26 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Final Draft, October 5 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Revised Shooting Script, October 16 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Revised Shooting Script, October 26 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Revised Shooting Script, November 14 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Finale, November 18 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Final Script, Master Copy, November 28 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Final Script, November 28 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Final Script Rewrites, November 28 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Final Script, December 8 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Cutting Script, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Looping Script, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dixie Scenes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Line Scripts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Scripts by Reel Number, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
  - Script Rewrites, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Script Revisions, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Script Revisions with Author Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Script Rewrites, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Cotton Club Revue and Scene Synopsis, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Production Memos, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Production Notes, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Staff and Crew List, Cast List, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Draft of Club Handbill, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Robert Duvall Tribute, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Publicity over Financing of The Cotton Club, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Publicity for The Cotton Club, 1983-1986; 1997; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - World Premiere of The Cotton Club, Invitation and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp"Vanity Fair (Folder 1 of 3), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp"Vanity Fair (Folders 2 and 3 of 3), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Foreign Publicity, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Murder of Roy Radin Clips, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp,"Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Cotton Club Memorabilia, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Ironweed (Film Version), 1981-1997; Undated; 8; 2.01 cu. ft.
  This series documents the transition of Ironweed from the 1983 award-winning novel to film in 1987. Like the book, the movie focuses on the character of Francis Phelan and his return to Albany during the Depression. William Kennedy wrote the script for the film which was directed by Hector Babenco and starred Jack Nicholson and Meryl Streep. It was filmed on location in Albany and the surrounding areas. The materials include many draft and edited scripts, publicity materials, information about casting and locations, call sheets, correspondence, reviews, and two paperback copies of the novel with notes used for script writing. Note the overall dates for the series are not inclusive.
  Please see Series 4, Ironweed, for materials related to the writing of the novel.
  - Climate Information, 1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Raw First Draft, August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scene Sequence with Author Edits, August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Author Notes, August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dialogue Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - First Computer Typed Draft, September 3 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Script with Author Edits, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Script with Author Edits, September 5 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Incomplete First Draft with Edits, September 5 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of First Draft Script, September 5 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Complete First Draft, September 5 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Copy of Second Draft with Author Edits, October 14 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Third Draft, October 19 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of [October 21, 1985] Script, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - First Draft with Changes Done with Hector Babenco, October 21 1985; October 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Second Draft with Author Edits, October 10 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Copy of Second Draft Script, October 11 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Copy of Second Draft with Author Edits, October 11 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Copy of Second Draft Script, October 13 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Superseded Pages, October 16 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Edited Pages, October 24 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Second Drafts with Author Edits, October 25 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of Location Scenes, October 25 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Revised Pages, October 26 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Copy of Second Drafts with Author Edits, October 27 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Complete Second Draft with No Edits, October 27 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Locations, Props, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Info. Regarding Casting, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Publicity, 1986-1988; 1993; 1997; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Revised and Edited Pages, January 20 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Revised Second Draft Script, January 21 1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Third Draft, January 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ironweed Script Location/Stage Breakdown, January 1987; Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Helen's Speech by Meryl Streep and Continuity Notes, January 1987; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Call Sheets, February-May 1987 (Oversized 5, Folder 6)
  - Revised Pages, March 2 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Additions to "Danny" Scene, March 5 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Helen Monologue, March 17 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Scene Edits, March 17 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Copy of Script with Revised Pages, March 17 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Taft Entertainment Bound Script (2 copies), March 17 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Hooverville Extra Lines, May 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Filming Schedules, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Radio News Broadcast on War of the Worlds, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Poor Little Lamb" Lyrics and Information, 1987; Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Writers Institute Events, 1987; 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Finale Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cast of Characters/Continuity Lists, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Two Copies of Ironweed Paperback Novel, Used for Scriptwriting with Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - American Film Article Drafts and Information, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Copies and Pull-outs from The Making of Ironweed, 1987-1988; 1993; Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - England/Ireland Reviews, 1988; 1990; Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Trolley Information, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "He's Me Pal" Lyrics, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ironweed Logo, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Quinn's Book, 1981-1988; Undated; 9; 2.91 cu. ft.
  Contains drafts, edited copies, the final version, and galleys of Quinn's Book, published by William Kennedy in 1988. Part of the "Albany Cycle," this novel also involves the extended Phelan family, but focuses on the nineteenth century life and adventures of an ancestor named Daniel Quinn. There are many edited and unedited versions of the manuscript; however, the majority of copies are undated. The archivist tried to arrange these undated drafts in chronological order based upon the edits in each version.
  - Early Versions of Quinn's Book, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Statement of Plan, Summary, Prologue, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Early Pages, Book I, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Original Pages, Began Anew, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First Draft of Chapters 1 and 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eight Drafts of Chapter 1, Including Orig. Version, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Five Drafts of Chapters 2, 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - One Draft of Chapter 1-3, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Three Drafts of Chapter 3, with Author Notes, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Refined Copy of First Draft, Pages 1-68, March 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 4, with Author Notes, March-May 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chapters 1-5, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 5, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chapters 1-4 with Changes to May 1985 Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Working Drafts and Notes for Chapter 6, May 1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 6 with Author Notes, including One Prior to January 20, 1986 Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Four Drafts of Chapter 7, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 8, including One Prior to and One Following January 20, 1986 Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chapters 5 Through 8, January 20 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Five Drafts of Chapter 9 with Notes, April 1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Two Drafts of Book II, Chapter 1, June 1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book II, Chapter 2 with Author Edits, July 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - One Draft of "The Dumb Cake" with Author Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - One Draft of "At the Races, At the Ball", September 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pages with Author Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pages 1-169 with Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pages 170-217 with Edits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pages 22-221, November 2 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Book II Revised and Edited Pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Edited Pages, March 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book II, Pages 220-282, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Book II, Pages 220-280, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Edited Pages, Pages 220-272, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reworking of Pages 273-285, Prior to June 11, 1987, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Edited Pages 273-307, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Edited Pages 288-337, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Edited Pages 293-317, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Edited Pages 306-339, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Edited Pages 317-334, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of Book I, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Book II, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Master Copy with Author's Editing, ca. June 10 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Edited Copy, Incomplete (Folder 1 of 2), Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Edited Copy, Incomplete (Folder 2 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Edited Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Book I, Pages 1-219 with Edits, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Book II, Pages 220-335 with Edits, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Copy of Book II, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photocopy Book I, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy Book II, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Book I with Edits, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Book II with Edits, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Unedited Copy of Book I, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Unedited Copy of Book II, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Unedited Photocopy of Book II, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Book I with Minor Edits, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Copy of Book II with Minor Edits, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Book I with Gerry Howard Edits, August 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Book II with Gerry Howard Edits, August 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Copy of Final Draft, Book I, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Copy of Final Draft, Book II, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Book I with Proof Reader's Marks, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Book II with Proof Reader's Marks, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs, 1987 (Oversized 4, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Quinn's Book, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Dead Matter" and Book Cover, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)